<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OSPFv3 on JulioPDX</title>
    <link>https://juliopdx.github.io/tags/ospfv3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OSPFv3 on JulioPDX</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliopdx.github.io/tags/ospfv3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aruba Spine Leaf Deployment With OSPFv3 and Link Local Addresses</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.github.io/2021/03/29/aruba-spine-leaf-deployment-with-ospfv3-and-link-local-addresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.github.io/2021/03/29/aruba-spine-leaf-deployment-with-ospfv3-and-link-local-addresses/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was recently on my way to finishing IPv6 Fundamentals by Rick Graziani. I will admit I’m not the fastest reader! In the book Rick mentions the following:
 You could configure router R2’s interfaces with only link-local addresses, no global unicast addresses. This is because R2 has no end user interfaces. RFC 7404, Using Only Link-Local Addressing inside an IPv6 Network, discusses implementing routing protocols using only link-local addresses on infrastructure links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aruba Spine Leaf With OSPFv3 and IPv6</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.github.io/2021/03/18/aruba-spine-leaf-with-ospfv3-and-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.github.io/2021/03/18/aruba-spine-leaf-with-ospfv3-and-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for checking out this post! In this post I hope to breakdown the topology you see above. I’ll walk through the design, IPv6 IP allocations, and OSPFv3. I have a very small background in IPv6, basically enough to get past a few Cisco exams, which inevitably gets forgotten about after some time of little to no use. I purchased IPv6 Fundamentals by Rick Graziani, I want to say almost a year ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
