<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BGP on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</title>
    <link>https://juliopdx.com/tags/bgp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BGP on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 14:18:17 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliopdx.com/tags/bgp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RPKI in the Lab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2023/01/02/rpki-in-the-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 14:18:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2023/01/02/rpki-in-the-lab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently finished the last chapters of Optimal Routing Design (great read). One of the chapters covered routing protocol security with protocols such as BGP, EIGRP, and OSPF. This echoed something in my head regarding Resource Public Key Infrastructure (RPKI). I knew the book&amp;rsquo;s printing was around 2003 and figured RPKI wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be in the book. This led me to wonder if I could get RPKI running in the lab, and the following blog post details some of that journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ExaBGP in the Lab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/25/exabgp-in-the-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 15:06:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/25/exabgp-in-the-lab/</guid>
      <description>Intro I was recently working my way through Optimal Routing design by Cisco Press&amp;hellip; Can you tell that I get through books very slowly? I&amp;rsquo;ve probably used that sentence in my blog posts three or four times now! Either way, this chapter focused on scaling BGP and dealing with external connections. The section that really got me was external connections. The books goes over a lot, for example, handling inbound traffic, outbound traffic, full routes vs partial vs default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Simulation Tools and Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/13/network-simulation-tools-and-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 21:07:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/13/network-simulation-tools-and-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been progressing through a series of technical books, some of which I&amp;rsquo;ve shared on other blogs. A few of them focus on BGP. BGP being so broad, I decided to create a challenge lab. Creating the challenge/troubleshooting labs has really made more concepts stick. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to use the principle of teaching someone to make the learning last. These have been incredibly fun to create and the community interaction has been amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multipoint Redistribution and SR Linux</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/22/multipoint-redistribution-and-sr-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 15:25:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/22/multipoint-redistribution-and-sr-linux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I’ve been working my way through Optimal Routing Design by Russ White, Don Slice, and Alvaro Retana. It has been a great read so far and I highly recommend it. When I work through a book I usually try and lab up any concept I can, this helps me make it stick as much as possible. Early on in the book the authors mention redistribution and possible issues that can come with doing it at more than one point in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Learning About Internet Exchange Points (IXPs)</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/08/29/my-journey-learning-about-internet-exchange-points-ixps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 18:04:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/08/29/my-journey-learning-about-internet-exchange-points-ixps/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello all and thank you for checking out one of my blog posts. Really means a lot! Have you ever heard IXP mentioned in network engineering speak and thought, what the heck is that? I definitely have, and in my day to day I don’t usually interact with an IXP at all. So here I am a curious individual, wanting to learn the things. I figured, what the heck, now is as good a time as any to deep dive some IXP knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
