<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NAPALM on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</title>
    <link>https://juliopdx.com/tags/napalm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NAPALM on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 11:26:48 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliopdx.com/tags/napalm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Network CI/CD Pipeline Part 4</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/10/31/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 11:26:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/10/31/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello everyone and thank you for checking out part four in this series. I went on vacation for a bit, but I’m glad to be back on the keys. In this post I will break down all of the steps performed before a change hits our network devices. This is important because we have the opportunity to stop incorrect or invalid configurations from ever hitting our network devices. A few steps that we will cover are: Black for code formatting, Batfish to validate configuration updates, and NAPALM dry run for testing the legitimacy of the configuration files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Validation With Nornir &amp; Napalm</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/02/27/network-validation-with-nornir-napalm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/02/27/network-validation-with-nornir-napalm/</guid>
      <description>Intro I wanted to get my feet wet with Nornir/NAPALM and Python network automation in general. One simple goal to start with in network automation is validating configurations or deploying “show commands” and returning some kind of useful information. I wanted to start with something very simple, as easy wins make me want to keep progressing. In this post I will break down how I validate SNMP information on network devices using Nornir and NAPALM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
