<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IPv6 on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</title>
    <link>https://juliopdx.com/tags/ipv6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IPv6 on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 18:04:42 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliopdx.com/tags/ipv6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Learning About Internet Exchange Points (IXPs)</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/08/29/my-journey-learning-about-internet-exchange-points-ixps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 18:04:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/08/29/my-journey-learning-about-internet-exchange-points-ixps/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello all and thank you for checking out one of my blog posts. Really means a lot! Have you ever heard IXP mentioned in network engineering speak and thought, what the heck is that? I definitely have, and in my day to day I don’t usually interact with an IXP at all. So here I am a curious individual, wanting to learn the things. I figured, what the heck, now is as good a time as any to deep dive some IXP knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Route Redistribution OSPFv3 and EIGRPv6</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/05/03/route-redistribution-ospfv3-and-eigrpv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/05/03/route-redistribution-ospfv3-and-eigrpv6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for checking out this post. I was recently working through OSPF and EIGRP for ENARSI studies and something came up on a lab I was building. Redistributing routes between OSPFv3 and EIGRPv6. I am specifically speaking of the IPv6 variant of these protocols.
In the topology you see below. We have three routing devices. One running only EIGRPv6, one running OSPFv3 (Aruba CX), and the redistribution node running both protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aruba Spine Leaf Deployment With OSPFv3 and Link Local Addresses</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/03/29/aruba-spine-leaf-deployment-with-ospfv3-and-link-local-addresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/03/29/aruba-spine-leaf-deployment-with-ospfv3-and-link-local-addresses/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was recently on my way to finishing IPv6 Fundamentals by Rick Graziani. I will admit I’m not the fastest reader! In the book Rick mentions the following:
 You could configure router R2’s interfaces with only link-local addresses, no global unicast addresses. This is because R2 has no end user interfaces. RFC 7404, Using Only Link-Local Addressing inside an IPv6 Network, discusses implementing routing protocols using only link-local addresses on infrastructure links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aruba Spine Leaf With OSPFv3 and IPv6</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/03/18/aruba-spine-leaf-with-ospfv3-and-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/03/18/aruba-spine-leaf-with-ospfv3-and-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for checking out this post! In this post I hope to breakdown the topology you see above. I’ll walk through the design, IPv6 IP allocations, and OSPFv3. I have a very small background in IPv6, basically enough to get past a few Cisco exams, which inevitably gets forgotten about after some time of little to no use. I purchased IPv6 Fundamentals by Rick Graziani, I want to say almost a year ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
