<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</title>
    <link>https://juliopdx.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 15:45:51 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliopdx.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning Labs With Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/28/learning-labs-with-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 15:45:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/28/learning-labs-with-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Hello Hello everyone and thank you for checking in. I’m back with another post. To be honest this one is not the norm as it will just redirect you to a project I’ve been working on with Containerlab. I’m still progressing through the Optimal Routing Design book by Cisco Press. I still haven’t finished the OSPF chapter but little by little.
A while back I mentioned that Containerlab could be an amazing resource in learning environments for individuals getting into IT or instructors trying to show students some routing design or technology involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning a Little About Search Algorithms With Python</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/12/learning-a-little-about-search-algorithms-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 15:12:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/12/learning-a-little-about-search-algorithms-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for tuning in to another episode. First off, I was recently notified that this blog made it to the Cisco IT Blog Awards final! Pretty wild to think about, but thank you to all those involved. This one is definitely going to be different and out of my comfort zone and I appreciate you sticking with me.
I have been working through the Introduction to Computer Science course by CS50x (Harvard).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey and Experience With Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/10/my-journey-and-experience-with-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 14:32:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/10/my-journey-and-experience-with-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Thank you all for checking out this post. This is going to be a special one. Due to the fact that I had such a joy using this new tool (new to me). I don’t like to over hype tools or new things just to hype it up. There are times where a tool or technology does deserve the credit and time in the limelight. I think Containerlabs is one of those tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Learning About Juniper Junos</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/06/my-journey-learning-about-juniper-junos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 13:57:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/06/my-journey-learning-about-juniper-junos/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for checking out another blog post. I’ve been under the weather for a bit but I am back on the keys. This post will be all about some neat things I discovered while learning a bit about the Juniper Junos NOS (network operating system). Previously I had never used Juniper, it was a vendor that always eluded me. My previous employers did not utilize this NOS and I never got around to adding it in the lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Learning About the Palo Alto Networks Python SDK</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/22/my-journey-learning-about-the-palo-alto-networks-python-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 13:18:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/22/my-journey-learning-about-the-palo-alto-networks-python-sdk/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for checking out another blog post. This one will be all about Python and Palo Alto Networks (PAN). I was recently going through a PAN Firewall course on Pluralsight by Craig Stansbury. Craig does an excellent job of walking learners through the process of administering and securing a PAN firewall. I wanted to take this opportunity to double dip and try to wrap my head around the PAN pan-os-python library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Network CI/CD Pipeline Part 6</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/12/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 12:26:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/12/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello all and thank you for tuning in to the last part of the network CI/CD series. It really means a lot and I hope you have learned a bit along the way. In this post we will focus on testing after a change is made, more specifically, we will be looking at Suzieq. If you stick around until the end, we will look at maintaining a “golden state” of configuration using cron and a message from Rocky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Network CI/CD Pipeline Part 5</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/08/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 11:58:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/08/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello all, thank you for reading the previous posts in this series. It has been fun interacting with all of you and see a few folks taking the challenge of standing this up on their own. In this post we will go over the framework that is performing our configuration deployments, Nornir and NAPALM. I will also provide an example worklflow on how this is all tied together and executed from a network engineers perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Network CI/CD Pipeline Part 4</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/10/31/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 11:26:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/10/31/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello everyone and thank you for checking out part four in this series. I went on vacation for a bit, but I’m glad to be back on the keys. In this post I will break down all of the steps performed before a change hits our network devices. This is important because we have the opportunity to stop incorrect or invalid configurations from ever hitting our network devices. A few steps that we will cover are: Black for code formatting, Batfish to validate configuration updates, and NAPALM dry run for testing the legitimacy of the configuration files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Generate Cisco Lifecycle Documentation With Python and APIs</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/09/23/how-to-generate-cisco-lifecycle-documentation-with-python-and-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 10:06:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/09/23/how-to-generate-cisco-lifecycle-documentation-with-python-and-apis/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was recently in a Twitter conversation with a few network engineers, in that feed was great dialogue on how often folks upgrade their network environments. Whether its when a massive vulnerability hits or just keeping up with vendor recommended releases. I mentioned that the Cisco Support APIs are an incredible resource. These APIs allow users with the appropriate access to get information about their devices. This could be recommended software releases, EoX dates, last day of support, vulnerabilities, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Network Icons for Labs With Python</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/09/17/converting-network-icons-for-labs-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 09:31:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/09/17/converting-network-icons-for-labs-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction First of all, the diagrams used in this post and repository were originally created by ecceman. Please head over to the original repository and show some love by giving it a star! When going through studies or testing a solution, I tend to lab a lot. On top of that I usually try and make my labs and topologies look pretty. I like to tell myself if the topology looks good, then I will learn more effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Nornir With FastAPI</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/09/01/integrating-nornir-with-fastapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 18:52:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/09/01/integrating-nornir-with-fastapi/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently saw a fellow engineer share an amazing article on Real Python. It was a post by Sebastián Ramírez, the creator of FastAPI. I’m fairly comfortable working with APIs but I’ve never even thought about making one. The prospect seems so daunting, especially when I’m still trying to master the foundational skills of python. FastAPI does a ton of heavy lifting to make this process incredibly easy to get started and build web APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating MPLS L3VPNs With Nornir</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/08/14/automating-mpls-l3vpns-with-nornir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 10:38:25 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/08/14/automating-mpls-l3vpns-with-nornir/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello all and thank you for checking out another one of my blog posts. It really means a lot. I recently completed the Cisco ENARSI exam after a few months of studying. It was honestly pretty difficult for me but the pass was worth it! I may have to write a blog post on studying for and passing that exam. In this post I will break down how I automated some parts of an MPLS L3VPN deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Slack Bot for Network Engineers</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/05/24/python-slack-bot-for-network-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:19:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/05/24/python-slack-bot-for-network-engineers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for joining me in another blog post. I’ve wanted to mess with getting a bot running on Slack for a while now. After coming across a fantastic post by Mason Egger at Digital Ocean (linked at the end), I figured now is as good a time as any. Think of that post as a prerequisite to get you started before following along with this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Validation With Nornir &amp; Napalm</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/02/27/network-validation-with-nornir-napalm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/02/27/network-validation-with-nornir-napalm/</guid>
      <description>Intro I wanted to get my feet wet with Nornir/NAPALM and Python network automation in general. One simple goal to start with in network automation is validating configurations or deploying “show commands” and returning some kind of useful information. I wanted to start with something very simple, as easy wins make me want to keep progressing. In this post I will break down how I validate SNMP information on network devices using Nornir and NAPALM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating List of IP Addresses With Ansible Filter Plugin</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/02/02/creating-list-of-ip-addresses-with-ansible-filter-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/02/02/creating-list-of-ip-addresses-with-ansible-filter-plugin/</guid>
      <description>Intro I recently had a use case where I needed a list of IP addresses from a prefix. My first step was to go through Ansible documentation on current filters to see if something would match my need. Long story short, there wasn’t. At least, nothing I could find which honestly is probably a huge possibility, and in that case this post is pointless. Ansible does have IP address filters but I noticed most all of the examples assume you already have a list of IP addresses to pass to the filters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
