<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Containerlab on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</title>
    <link>https://juliopdx.com/tags/containerlab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Containerlab on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:53:36 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliopdx.com/tags/containerlab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NATS and Configuration Minions</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2024/12/02/nats-and-configuration-minions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:53:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2024/12/02/nats-and-configuration-minions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Two blogs in one year. Who do I think I am? In all seriousness, thank you for all the feedback on the previous blog. As always, it really means a lot. This one might go a bit sideways, but building something like this has always been on my mind, and I got another spark to get it done while attending AutoCon2.
I caught the first half of a talk by Mircea Ulinic from Digitial Ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codespaces for Network Engineers and Educators</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2024/11/25/codespaces-for-network-engineers-and-educators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:08:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2024/11/25/codespaces-for-network-engineers-and-educators/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Can you believe it&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since my last blog? It&amp;rsquo;s incredible how fast time flies. Thank you all for continuing to read the blog and sharing it with engineers in the community. I can&amp;rsquo;t thank you enough for all the support and encouragement I&amp;rsquo;ve received on this journey.
This blog is going to take a bit of a turn. I usually write in the form of a tool I have used or been presented with and think, &amp;ldquo;This is incredible; more people should know about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network CI and Open Source</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2023/11/25/network-ci-and-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 19:33:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2023/11/25/network-ci-and-open-source/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Wow, it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since my last blog post. I recently attended the first AutoCon event focusing on network automation. Long story short, it was terrific. Check it out and be on the lookout for the next one. Shortly after AutoCon, two community members sprung up with sweet blog posts. My colleague and friend Dan Hertzberg are resurrecting the blog. The first post went over leveraging ygot to create Go structs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPKI in the Lab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2023/01/02/rpki-in-the-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 14:18:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2023/01/02/rpki-in-the-lab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently finished the last chapters of Optimal Routing Design (great read). One of the chapters covered routing protocol security with protocols such as BGP, EIGRP, and OSPF. This echoed something in my head regarding Resource Public Key Infrastructure (RPKI). I knew the book&amp;rsquo;s printing was around 2003 and figured RPKI wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be in the book. This led me to wonder if I could get RPKI running in the lab, and the following blog post details some of that journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node Connections With Netreplica and Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/03/28/node-connections-with-netreplica-and-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 12:08:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/03/28/node-connections-with-netreplica-and-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Thank you all for checking out another blog post. All the support for the blog has been tremendous and I can&amp;rsquo;t thank you all enough. Packet Pushers invited me to write on their platform and it&amp;rsquo;s been a pleasure working with Drew and team. If you would like to check those out, I will link them at the end of this post! Today we will focus on an interesting tool in the community, Netreplica, but specifically Graphite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Simulation Tools and Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/13/network-simulation-tools-and-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 21:07:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/13/network-simulation-tools-and-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been progressing through a series of technical books, some of which I&amp;rsquo;ve shared on other blogs. A few of them focus on BGP. BGP being so broad, I decided to create a challenge lab. Creating the challenge/troubleshooting labs has really made more concepts stick. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to use the principle of teaching someone to make the learning last. These have been incredibly fun to create and the community interaction has been amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multipoint Redistribution and SR Linux</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/22/multipoint-redistribution-and-sr-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 15:25:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/22/multipoint-redistribution-and-sr-linux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I’ve been working my way through Optimal Routing Design by Russ White, Don Slice, and Alvaro Retana. It has been a great read so far and I highly recommend it. When I work through a book I usually try and lab up any concept I can, this helps me make it stick as much as possible. Early on in the book the authors mention redistribution and possible issues that can come with doing it at more than one point in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey and Experience With Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/10/my-journey-and-experience-with-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 14:32:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/10/my-journey-and-experience-with-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Thank you all for checking out this post. This is going to be a special one. Due to the fact that I had such a joy using this new tool (new to me). I don’t like to over hype tools or new things just to hype it up. There are times where a tool or technology does deserve the credit and time in the limelight. I think Containerlabs is one of those tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
