<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</title>
    <link>https://juliopdx.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 21:07:43 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliopdx.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Network Simulation Tools and Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/13/network-simulation-tools-and-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 21:07:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/13/network-simulation-tools-and-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been progressing through a series of technical books, some of which I&amp;rsquo;ve shared on other blogs. A few of them focus on BGP. BGP being so broad, I decided to create a challenge lab. Creating the challenge/troubleshooting labs has really made more concepts stick. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to use the principle of teaching someone to make the learning last. These have been incredibly fun to create and the community interaction has been amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Labs With Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/28/learning-labs-with-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 15:45:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/28/learning-labs-with-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone and thank you for checking in. I’m back with another post. To be honest this one is not the norm as it will just redirect you to a project I’ve been working on with Containerlab. I’m still progressing through the Optimal Routing Design book by Cisco Press. I still haven’t finished the OSPF chapter but little by little.
A while back I mentioned that Containerlab could be an amazing resource in learning environments for individuals getting into IT or instructors trying to show students some routing design or technology involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIGRP Network Design in the Lab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/25/eigrp-network-design-in-the-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 15:50:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/25/eigrp-network-design-in-the-lab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I just finished the chapter on EIGRP network design in Optimal Routing Design (Cisco Press), I wanted to provide a high level overview of what I learned and incorporated that in the lab. This book really has been great as it provides advanced routing techniques but keeps it in a maintainable format. I hope you enjoy the post and learn something along the way. I would advise you to research on your own and compare the pros and cons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multipoint Redistribution and SR Linux</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/22/multipoint-redistribution-and-sr-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 15:25:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/22/multipoint-redistribution-and-sr-linux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I’ve been working my way through Optimal Routing Design by Russ White, Don Slice, and Alvaro Retana. It has been a great read so far and I highly recommend it. When I work through a book I usually try and lab up any concept I can, this helps me make it stick as much as possible. Early on in the book the authors mention redistribution and possible issues that can come with doing it at more than one point in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning a Little About Search Algorithms With Python</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/12/learning-a-little-about-search-algorithms-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 15:12:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/12/learning-a-little-about-search-algorithms-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for tuning in to another episode. First off, I was recently notified that this blog made it to the Cisco IT Blog Awards final! Pretty wild to think about, but thank you to all those involved. This one is definitely going to be different and out of my comfort zone and I appreciate you sticking with me.
I have been working through the Introduction to Computer Science course by CS50x (Harvard).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey and Experience With Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/10/my-journey-and-experience-with-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 14:32:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/10/my-journey-and-experience-with-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Thank you all for checking out this post. This is going to be a special one. Due to the fact that I had such a joy using this new tool (new to me). I don’t like to over hype tools or new things just to hype it up. There are times where a tool or technology does deserve the credit and time in the limelight. I think Containerlabs is one of those tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Learning About Juniper Junos</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/06/my-journey-learning-about-juniper-junos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 13:57:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/12/06/my-journey-learning-about-juniper-junos/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for checking out another blog post. I’ve been under the weather for a bit but I am back on the keys. This post will be all about some neat things I discovered while learning a bit about the Juniper Junos NOS (network operating system). Previously I had never used Juniper, it was a vendor that always eluded me. My previous employers did not utilize this NOS and I never got around to adding it in the lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Learning About the Palo Alto Networks Python SDK</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/22/my-journey-learning-about-the-palo-alto-networks-python-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 13:18:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/22/my-journey-learning-about-the-palo-alto-networks-python-sdk/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello and thank you for checking out another blog post. This one will be all about Python and Palo Alto Networks (PAN). I was recently going through a PAN Firewall course on Pluralsight by Craig Stansbury. Craig does an excellent job of walking learners through the process of administering and securing a PAN firewall. I wanted to take this opportunity to double dip and try to wrap my head around the PAN pan-os-python library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Network CI/CD Pipeline Part 6</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/12/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 12:26:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/12/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello all and thank you for tuning in to the last part of the network CI/CD series. It really means a lot and I hope you have learned a bit along the way. In this post we will focus on testing after a change is made, more specifically, we will be looking at Suzieq. If you stick around until the end, we will look at maintaining a “golden state” of configuration using cron and a message from Rocky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Network CI/CD Pipeline Part 5</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/08/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 11:58:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2021/11/08/building-a-network-ci/cd-pipeline-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello all, thank you for reading the previous posts in this series. It has been fun interacting with all of you and see a few folks taking the challenge of standing this up on their own. In this post we will go over the framework that is performing our configuration deployments, Nornir and NAPALM. I will also provide an example worklflow on how this is all tied together and executed from a network engineers perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
