<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OSPF on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</title>
    <link>https://juliopdx.com/tags/ospf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OSPF on Welcome to the World of Tomorrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:08:58 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliopdx.com/tags/ospf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Codespaces for Network Engineers and Educators</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2024/11/25/codespaces-for-network-engineers-and-educators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:08:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2024/11/25/codespaces-for-network-engineers-and-educators/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Can you believe it&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since my last blog? It&amp;rsquo;s incredible how fast time flies. Thank you all for continuing to read the blog and sharing it with engineers in the community. I can&amp;rsquo;t thank you enough for all the support and encouragement I&amp;rsquo;ve received on this journey.
This blog is going to take a bit of a turn. I usually write in the form of a tool I have used or been presented with and think, &amp;ldquo;This is incredible; more people should know about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Simulation Tools and Containerlab</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/13/network-simulation-tools-and-containerlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 21:07:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/02/13/network-simulation-tools-and-containerlab/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been progressing through a series of technical books, some of which I&amp;rsquo;ve shared on other blogs. A few of them focus on BGP. BGP being so broad, I decided to create a challenge lab. Creating the challenge/troubleshooting labs has really made more concepts stick. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to use the principle of teaching someone to make the learning last. These have been incredibly fun to create and the community interaction has been amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multipoint Redistribution and SR Linux</title>
      <link>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/22/multipoint-redistribution-and-sr-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 15:25:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliopdx.com/2022/01/22/multipoint-redistribution-and-sr-linux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I’ve been working my way through Optimal Routing Design by Russ White, Don Slice, and Alvaro Retana. It has been a great read so far and I highly recommend it. When I work through a book I usually try and lab up any concept I can, this helps me make it stick as much as possible. Early on in the book the authors mention redistribution and possible issues that can come with doing it at more than one point in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
